web developer

huyhuynh

huyhuynh85@gmail.com 408.910.1012

PROFILE

My passion for creating and tinkering led me to switch to a career where I can make meaningful things that enrich the lives of others while also giving back to the community. I bring with me teamwork, analytical and communication skills carefully developed over the past six years from the marketing, marketing research and publishing industries.

EXPERIENCE

Graduate 2015

Dev Bootcamp

- Completed a 19-week immersive web development program
- Focused on Object Oriented Programing, Rails and JavaScript
- Emphasized Git, continuous integration and testing
- Provided constant feedback and employed empathetic approaches to other students and staff

Motorcycle Rider Coach

2012-now

Northern Illinois University

- Lead groups of students and teach them the fundamentals of motorcycle operation and safety
- Manage and reduce risk to maintain a safe learning environment

Accountant/Payroll

2014-2015

rEvolution Marketing

- Worked with multiple departments to migrate all current and historical accounting/HR data to new systems
- Ensured vendors/payroll checks were paid properly and on time

Accountant/Project Manager

2010-2014

Fieldwork Chicago O'Hare

- Provided a high quality of service through managing research projects and recruiters
- Hired and trained over half of client service staff
- Managed all cashflow including keeping up with collections and cutting costs

EDUCATION

University of California at Santa Barbara

2004-2008

- Bachelor of Arts in Business Economics with Accounting Emphasis
- Studied Globalization at Fudan University in Shanghai, China, Fall 2007

SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Git, API, JavaScript, AJAX, jQuery, CSS, Sass, HTML5, Bootstrap, ActiveRecord, PostgreSQL, SQLite, RSpec, Capybara, Jasmine, Teamwork, Customer Service, Time Management

PROJECTS

Friendlier May 2015

Rails

A dating site for friends to vet your potential dates before you meet them. Features image uploads and user messaging.

ShinetheChi June 2015

Rails

Mobile first app to view and report 311 service requests through Chicago's API. Features Bootstap grid and Google Maps.

Little Victories May 2015

Sinatra

Users can save and read small successes made throughout the year. Features AJAX and taggings.

DBoards May 2015

Sinatra

A CRUD app that allows anyone to upload and tag images of whiteboards. Features tagging and uploads.